Andrei Nicolae Tuță

074 93935418 tuta.andrei96@gmail.com February, 2021

Professional Profile

Versatile professional with development experience ranging in size from small private projects to full-scale applications. Currently working on developing an online and mobile e-commerce product's functionality and CRM, entrusted worldwide by customers.

Always interested in learning more about emerging OSS technologies and make new professional connections.

Professional History

Aeroparker

Stockport, UK Oct 2018 - present

 $Java\ Developer$

• Team leader: Managing a team of 4 developers working in a SCRUM framework.

- **Spring expertise**: Developed implementations of Spring based microservice applications using JOOQ, JWT, SQS and Thymeleaf.
- **BI tool**: Developed a BI tool used daily by a large number of clients to get product metrics through API calls and using D3.js for visualisation (to be improved using R and Python).
- Java system: Planned, designed and implemented new features for the Java core project, built using Apache Tomcat, AJAX and JSP.

• Birmingham City University

Birmingham, UK

Technical Student Assistant

Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

- Student Assistant: Managed and aided groups of students during courses and activities. Tasks varied explaining programming concepts and active development to
- Student Ambassador: Organised large scale events and provided tech support and resources.
- Innovation Fest Mentor: Supervised two teams of students with the planning, technical development and pitching of their entries for a local technology contest, which they won.

• Oracle Romania

Bucharest, RO

 $Database\ Administrator$

Jun - Sep 2017

- Oracle DBA training: Received training covering topics such as administration, back-up, recovery and automation.
- MySQL: Participated in guided bootcamps on MySQL and Orace SQL

• Logika IT Solutions

Bucharest, RO

Junior Database Administrator

Jun - Aug 2016

• Summer internship: Worked as a trainee in a team of 4 people managing databases for multiple clients. Other responsibilities included writing reports and suggestions on ways to improve the work-flow and diminish cost.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java, Javascript, SQL, Python
- Technologies: AWS(EC2, S3, SQS), Springboot, Tomcat 7&9, node-modules, MySQL, Testing (JUnit Jupiter, Mockito, Selenium), Flask, Jinja, Docker, Git
- Spoken Languages: Romanian, English, French, Spanish

EDUCATION

• Secretary

PR & note-taking.

• Birmingham City University

Data Analysis, Software Engineering & Database administration 2015 - 2018 • Universidad de Alcala Alcala de Henares, SP Software Design, Cloud computing & Agile Development Jan - Jun 2017 EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES CodeUp Stockport Participant Jul 2019 - Mar 2020 Participating and helping our members at our monthly Meetups. Medium Writing articles featuring subjects related to programming & literature. 2017 - present • Camp counselor URJ 6Points Sci tech Assisted & organised programming workshops for campers on Java & Processing Jun - Aug 2018 • Society Advisor HaCS Planned and volunteered for hosting local Hackathons. Sep 2015 - Jun 2018 • President BCU RoSoc Event planning, budgeting & team management. 2016 - 2018

Birmingham, UK

Rotaract Club Birmingham

2015 - 2017